Yeah, that's about right.
Yep.
Thanks, mate!
Are you alright there?
Fine.
Sorry?
I'm fine. Where's my tea?
I didn't know you wanted one. Would
you like me to put the kettle on?
No, no. I'm fine.
Oh. OK, just hold it there,
thanks, mate. Hold up.
Thank you.
Slow.
Thanks, mate.
Righto, come through.
Jesus, stop the car! Arggh!
Sir, are you alright? Are you hurt?!
Alright, I'm gonna try
and open the door, alright?
Oh, he smells like a brewery.
I was going to bring you that cuppa.
Looked like hard work out there.
It is.
Don't we have a vacuum cleaner for
that sort of thing?
It's not working.
Well, you know there's an appliance
fair at the co-op this week.
Oh! You'll enjoy that.
I'll get it.
Dr Blake's surgery.
One moment, please.
It's for you.
Oh, Danny. How's your morning?
Terrible!
Almost got killed. How about you?
Yes, me too. What's the story?
Straightforward drunk driver.
I'll just leave it to Gus.
Right, so, everyone's safe.
Who was it?
Travelling salesman. He died at the
scene on the Creswick Road.
And how do we know he's a salesman?
Oh, backseat of the car
was full of gear.
Head back to the crash site,
look through his car.
Make sure you get the man's
personals.
Can I take a car?
That bloke wrecked my pushie.
Walk. Be good for you -
and you can go home.
There's nothing here for you.
Good. Right. Well, feel free to waste
my time whenever it suits.
Uh, Doc? Doc, Doc?
Yes?
What would make a bloke's face turn
blue?
Gus! I was curious too.
What do you make of the colour?
Professional curiosity,
or are you just here to annoy me?
As always, Gus, I'm here to help.
Hey!
You should have seen
your face.
Do you mind?!
You actually left the ground!
Yeah, very bloody funny, alright?!
Oh, there's no need to be like that.
I was nearly killed earlier today,
so it's not a joke, alright?
Well, maybe you need to toughen up
a little bit there.
Don't suppose I could grab a lift.
Come on, it's halfway out of town!
Well, maybe that'll teach you not to
bite my head off next time.
The walk'll do you good,
get that blood pumping.
Ray Beck, travelling salesman.
Looks like a film star.
Women must've been all over him.
Do I detect a hint of envy there,
Gus? Done the bloods?
Not yet.
Obviously another drink driver.
Really?
You didn't smell his clothes?
No, but I smelled his mouth.
No trace.
You'd expect something there,
wouldn't you?
Colour suggests asphyxiation,
wouldn't you think?
Haemorrhagic stroke?
Hmm, might be right.
Cracked sternum. Minimal bruising.
I think he was dead
before he crashed the car.
Can I see his clothes?
Arggh!
Help yourself - his clothes.
They're too sharp for my taste.
Oh, I find that hard to believe, Gus.
Phew, I see what you mean
about the alcohol.
His trousers are covered in it.
Actually, only one leg.
Gus.
What do you make of these?
Acute infection
or some kind of poisoning.
Snake bite.
Arggh! Arggh!
Arggh!
Lawson.
I told you to go home.
Is Danny still at the crash?
Yep.
You told him to search that car,
didn't you?
Yeah, why?
He might be in trouble.
Some help here! Mattie?
Get some help here!
Take his shoulders.
Right, oxygen, now!
I've got the treatment room
prepped! What kind of snake?
I don't know.
We can't give him anti-venom
if we don't know what kind of snake
it was.
I don't know!
Right, on my 'three'.
One, two, three.
Pulse.
Onto it.
110.
Blake.
The men are looking for the snake.
They still haven't found it.
What do we do now?
Haemotoxic, cytoxic,
neurotoxic.
Haemotoxic, cytoxic...
Haemotoxic?
But from what you said, there was
obvious neural dysfunction.
What are you talking about?
We can't give him anti-venom
if we don't know what kind of snake
it was.
Can we give him something else?
We have three generalised vaccines.
Well, use one of those.
We don't know what the poison is...
Pulse again, please, please, please.
120.
He's in shock.
Danny!
Snake bite.
What kind of snake?
We don't know.
Well, what are you gonna do?
Blake.
Lucien!
Blake?
What kind of snake?
I don't know.
Well, we can't give him anti-venom
if we don't know what kind of snake
it was.
Lucien?
Pit viper. Asian pit viper.
Asian?!
Native to Asia.
Not an Australian snake.
Two deep puncture marks from hollow
fangs. Very, very distinctive.
No Australian snake
has fangs quite like it.
You've treated a viper snake bite
before.
No, but I've read about it.
Are you sure about this?
Not 100%, no.
But as sure as you possibly can be?
Please clear the room. Jean?
I'll wait in the corridor.
Alright, Mattie, haemotoxic.
Good.
120 over 80.
He's going to be alright.
Oh, thank God!
Perhaps he should stay with us until
he's feeling better.
Of course! Absolutely.
Well done.
An Asian pit viper.
Hmm. An educated guess.
How did a deadly foreign snake
get into that salesman's car?
Well, snakes crawl into cars
all the time.
Not Asian pit vipers, not here.
Well, some idiot bought it into the
country, let it escape.
Good job, Lucien.
Thank you, Matthew.
Right, see you again next week.
Claire Connolly!
How are you?
I can't find anything specifically
wrong with you, Mrs Connolly,
however, in general you are certainly
run-down.
Your heart rate is normal, your blood
pressure's a little high.
Have you been under
much stress lately?
My husband and I,
we run a boarding house.
There's been some drama lately.
One of the guests died in a car
crash.
Ray Beck.
You know him?
Not really, no.
I gather he sold vacuum cleaners.
Apparently he was the best.
You know, my housekeeper is in need
of a new vacuum cleaner.
Oh. The house is full of salesmen.
You could name your price.
Latest model - the Constellation,
for your delight.
It is, as they say, pure heaven.
Heaven?
Mm-hm.
For the lady, therefore,
for the gentleman.
What about the Canterbury?
Hubby's on a budget, is he?
Erm, I'm just the housekeeper.
My apologies.
Like I said, free delivery, free
bags, one year's free servicing.
There's a sucker born every day.
This is my sale.
Jim Thurlston.
District's top salesman,
all domestic appliances.
Second top seller.
Haven't you noticed?
Ray's no longer with us.
Ray Beck, the chap who died?
That's right.
Bloke had the most amazing contacts,
especially in refrigeration.
Look, I just couldn't compete.
He's gone. I'm top dog now.
Gentlemen, surely a little healthy
competition isn't a bad thing.
Fine by me. That's because mulleton
here is never gonna match me.
Well, I'm off to find a cup of tea.
Hubby might leave you with it.
Hand on heart, all the ladies swear
by the Constellation.
You want a real deal?
Talk to the real salesman.
Mrs Connolly?
Mrs Connolly? Hello?
Don't you yell at me,
Frank Connolly!
Come here, woman!
I will bloody yell at you if I want
to. I have had it up to here...
You've had it?
Yes, I bloody have!
I hate you so much!
Don't you walk away from me!
Don't you give me orders.
Come here, woman!
See that?
Perfect suction every time.
Exactly the same model I was
offering.
But with free bags.
I said free bags.
Year's warranty.
I can do that too.
Two sets of bags, year's warranty,
cost price.
How do I know it's the model
I really want?
You can borrow mine, try it out
and see if you like it.
Oh, thank you.
And if you like it,
do we have a deal?
There you are.
The A... the Asian pit viper hates
the cold, so that snake...
You know, the snake, there's no way
it would survive out here in the
bush.
What?!
The...
Never mind. How is it?
Well, it's fine, but it's not
picking up as well as it was before.
I think we need to empty the bag.
I'm sure that's probably relatively
easy to sort out.
Well, maybe you could do it for me.
Yes, of course.
I'm sure it's just a matter
of unfastening something on the side
or the back or...
There we are.
Oh, yeah!
'Relatively easy'?
Well, if it would just
do as it's told. Oh!
Don't worry, I'll fix all that up.
Hang on.
Constable, we'll need access
into here.
Go and get the key
from Frank Connolly.
Sorry to disturb you
at a time like this.
Was the missus happy with the vacuum
she borrowed?
Yeah, the missus was ecstatic,
thank you.
Then I'll drop the machine
over tomorrow.
Tell me, was Mr Churchill
disappointed
he missed out on the sale?
It's dog eat dog in our line of
work, Doc.
Yeah.
What's with all the coppers?
Oh, I couldn't possibly comment,
Mr Thurlston. If you'll excuse me.
Is there a law against keeping a few
snakes or something?
Mmm, there is. You broke it.
I understand a Mr Raymond Beck
was staying here, Mr Connolly.
Yeah, he was.
You know that he died?
Car crash, I heard. Hate to think
that booze was behind it.
He could always put it away.
Well, there's more than the car
crash.
He died from snake bite, and then
a young constable of mine got bitten
while he was searching his car
down near Kilburn.
The thing's still on the loose.
Now, you've got an empty cage
downstairs
that's supposed to have an Asian pit
viper inside.
Yeah, I didn't know it was missing
till that bloke broke in.
Where's the snake now?
No idea!
What do you mean,
you've got no idea?
It's supposed to be
in the bloody cage.
But I honestly don't know.
Look, I told you.
I always keep the key to the
basement on me.
I used to have a spare key, but...
Missing too, is it?
I've got a dead man who stayed here
and a young constable in hospital,
both bitten by a snake,
and you know nothing about it.
I need you to come down the station
and make a statement.
My men are going
to search Mr Beck's car,
and if they find a snake
and it's an Asian pit viper,
I'm charging you with murder.
This is where Ray Beck
was staying.
It's alright, Mrs Connolly.
I'm sure this situation
isn't helping those issues
we discussed in my surgery.
If you feel the need to come back
and see me again, please do.
I do have to ask you a question,
I'm afraid.
Your husband mentioned the spare key
to the basement went missing.
Now, is this right?
Frank looked after the keys.
The basement wasn't
any of my business.
Of course.
Just one more thing, if I may.
Ray Beck was a very handsome man.
Did your husband have any reason,
any reason, to be jealous?
She was having an affair?
She's unhappy.
She has an affair with the handsome
salesman in the upstairs room,
then hubby finds out and sticks his
deadliest snake in her lover's car.
Well, how do you know she was
unhappy?
I heard them arguing. I was hiding in
their kitchen at the time.
You should've seen her expression
when you mentioned Ray Beck.
She was almost in tears!
The way she folded his clothes.
By the way,
did you find his sales notebook?
Apparently Ray was the region's top
seller,
but his notebook wasn't in his jacket
at the hospital.
Haven't found it. Why?
Their notebooks contain their
contacts,
and they treat these books like the
holy grail.
Word is that Ray's contacts were the
best.
No, haven't found it,
but there was something else.
The man liked to punt.
All these are marked 'unpaid'.
Goodness! £200, that's a lot to owe.
If it's the bookie I'm thinking of,
he wouldn't have been happy that
Beck couldn't pay.
Eddie Carlin, real lowlife.
Has a particular way
of writing his numbers.
Saw young Parks today.
Looks like he's on the mend.
Close thing, but yes.
Lawson.
Yep.
It's Hobart.
They've found the snake.
Well?
Yeah.
That's a pit viper.
Frank Connolly, I'm arresting you on
the charges of murder,
attempted murder, possession of
dangerous animals as defined in the
relevant Acts.
You don't have to say anything at
this time,
but anything you say or do may be
given in evidence.
Do you understand?
Take him down.
Mrs Connolly.
Are they charging Frank?
Yes, they are. Can you... can you
tell me what happened?
There's no way he would have
ever hurt Ray.
Well, that's not how it looks,
Mrs Connolly.
Now, I know you and your husband
weren't exactly happy.
But Frank wouldn't hurt anyone.
Wives often say that, Mrs Connolly.
But I know Frank!
Then please tell me
what happened with Ray.
Oh!
Mrs Connolly!
No admissions yet, but that'll come.
What about that bookie
you were talking about?
Carlin? Lowlife scum.
Have to get him on something else.
Mr Carlin will see you now.
Yep, righto, Harry.
Yep, right, OK, gotcha. See ya.
Ray Beck said you'd give good odds at
today's meet at Flemington.
Ray Beck ain't worth a toss.
Don't bring idiots like this in here
again.
Come on.
Wait!
Listen, I need to place a few bets,
and I'm guessing Ray owing you
money's left a bit of a hole.
What do you know about Beck?
That he died.
Real shame.
Must've been somewhat annoying,
Ray dying and owing you money.
You talk too much.
Hello? Ah, yeah. Spring flutter?
OK, mate. Yep, see ya.
Look, I'd like to take a piece of
that action, if I may.
Spring Flutter for a win in the
fourth.
20:1.
5, and Landed Gentry for a place in
the sixth, £5.
16:1.
Good.
I guess it's not really in your
interests to kill someone
if they owe you money.
Sterling Silver in the ninth.
Winner or place, £5.
You kill them, you don't get your
money back, do you?
Well, if depends.
I need to set an example.
And how would you do that, exactly?
Would you ever use a snake to make an
example of someone?
Who is this guy, boss?
I've no idea, Maurice.
But he's lucky, he's lucky you got
a sense of humour.
Yeah.
You've probably got less than five
seconds
to tell me exactly what you want.
Right, well, when you put it that
way, I... Please, just...
I just need to find out more about
Ray Beck.
Nothing about you.
Oh, why didn't you say so?
Rubbish punter!
He owed me 200 quid. He's lucky
I didn't get to him first.
Pretty boy.
Apparently the bloke couldn't keep
it in his pants.
It's almost
a dead heat
between Acapella
and Sterling Silver.
It'll be remembered for the fourth
that lasted longer than the race.
Mr Carlin said there wasn't much
return for you today.
Oh, I don't know.
I think I got what I needed.
Oh, and he said to say you're
welcome back at any time.
Well, thank you, Maurice.
You tell Mr Carlin I'm honoured.
Hi! How are you feeling?
Yeah, pretty weak still.
I'm not surprised.
I brought you something.
Thanks.
It was the least I can do.
You feel up for this?
Yeah.
What sort?
You choose.
Oh.
What?
I'm sorry.
You should see your face.
Oh, I can't believe you were gonna
feed that to me!
That's hilarious!
Ma... Mattie!
Oh!
Bloody...
Jean?
I see your new vacuum's arrived.
Oh, has it?
Yes.
I thought you might've unpacked it
by now.
Now, I've had other things to do.
Right. Here's hoping it makes
something of a difference, eh?
Tell me, what do you know about the
Connollys?
The Connollys - married young.
The house has been in the family
for years.
Frank and Claire have had to rent
rooms out.
Hard times?
Hard times. Pass the whetstone?
Yes.
Frank was a champion full forward
till he did his knee.
She's nice. Seems unhappy.
I wouldn't have thought he's the
kind of man who would kill anyone,
though.
Well, did you think
he was the kind of man
who'd keep snakes in his basement?
Oh, I stand corrected!
Any reason for the unhappiness?
Should there be?
Well, yes, I'd have thought so.
Oh, why don't you ask her yourself?
Huh. I have absolutely no idea.
Really? No idea at all?
No. I missed something?
No, I'm sure you're right.
It's probably just that time of the
month or the stars have aligned...
Mattie.
I'm sure Jean loves
being taken for granted
just as much as the rest of us,
and God help us all if any of us
started complaining.
The whole bloody world would end.
Yes?! Dr Lucien Blake.
I wouldn't have called you.
The bloke doesn't seem to be in
any danger. It's just... strange.
Has he been this way the whole time?
Usually used to the blokes who want
to take me on.
Mr Connolly!
You need me to stay?
No, I'll be fine.
Mr Connolly, it's Dr Blake.
Is there anything I can do for you?
I want to die.
Mr Connolly, whatever you say to me
I will hold in the strictest
confidence.
Claire never deserved this.
Deserved what?
Mr Connolly, please.
Leave me alone.
Morning. Are you alright to walk?
Jean...
How are you?
Fine.
You're gonna be a bit slow
for a while.
I'm fine!
You're coming to stay with us for a
few days. I'll set up the spare
room.
Is Mattie gonna be there?
Yeah.
Right.
Well, come on through. We'll get you
settled and I'll pop the kettle on.
Hey.
Oh, I was rather enjoying that.
G'day.
I'll put you here, Danny,
till I've set up the spare room.
Yes.
I'll leave you to it.
You're not staying for lunch,
Mattie?
Uh, no, I'm going out.
I might get you to drop me at work,
if that's alright.
Boss doesn't like being a man down,
and the boys have been covering for
me...
No, no, no, no, Danny.
You're just out of hospital.
Doc, I'm good, and I don't wanna be
hanging around, you know?
Danny, I really would...
I'm fine, really!
I'll be on my way.
Thank you, Mrs Thompson.
You take care now.
New hobby.
Hmm.
What do you think of him?
Too smooth for my taste.
What about him?
Well, he's fine if you're
a 16-year-old girl,
but the rest of us have more
important things to worry about.
What would you think
if I started cutting these chaps out
of our magazines?
Yes.
Just returning your vacuum cleaner.
Oh! Mrs Beazley says thank you.
I'm afraid we had a blockage.
Your husband...
He's innocent!
They should let him go.
Claire, how long have you known?
When did you first realise Frank was
homosexual?
He'd beat you to a pulp if you'd
said that to his face!
Yes, he probably would,
but I think it's also the reason
he's currently catatonic on the floor
of a cell back at the police station.
Is he alright?
He's not doing well.
He's in deep trauma.
Can I see him?
Not till he goes to remand.
Now, your husband and Ray were
lovers, weren't they?
Claire, it's not your fault.
It's not his fault.
In fact, it's not even a question of
fault.
Modern research...
What does modern research
know about my marriage?!
Probably not much, but it suggests,
it suggests,
that this has been a part of Frank
right from the very beginning,
right from the start, just like hair
colour or eye colour.
This has nothing to do with you.
I didn't understand at first.
I just thought it was me.
I started to wonder.
Then I found him with someone.
He said he'd change,
but he couldn't.
So, Ray wasn't your husband's
first lover?
No, there were others.
Sometimes the men
who passed through here.
He only met Ray a few months ago.
I had never seen him
like this before.
He was...
Happy.
Claire, do you think your husband
could have killed Ray?
He couldn't have.
He loved him.
So, what's this about?
Connolly and Beck were lovers.
Trying to eat my lunch!
I'm sorry to offend
your sensibilities.
You realise that if this is true,
I'll have to charge Connolly
with unnatural acts on top of
everything else.
Well, you could,
but I hope you don't.
Where did this piece of information
come from?
Well, I completely missed it,
but Ray had the only single room in
the place -
a place where everyone else has to
share.
Doesn't mean he's a...
No, no, no, but Frank Connolly was
the one who assigned the rooms.
His wife confirmed it.
Always thought she was
a reasonable-looking woman, myself.
Yes, and Eddie Carlin told me Ray
couldn't keep it in his trousers.
Eddie Carlin?
Mmm.
Of course, we all assumed he was
talking about the ladies,
and I thought Claire and Connolly
were fighting over Ray,
and of course, they were,
only not quite as I imagined.
Maybe they were just a couple of
blokes having a little tiff.
Well, Claire doesn't think so.
It sounded like they were soul mates.
Oh!
So, I may have encouraged you to
arrest the wrong man.
Still, means we can rule out
Eddie Carlin.
Jesus, Blake.
You don't think Mrs Connolly...
Took revenge on her husband's lover?
Possibly, but I doubt it.
Parks, get me the Connolly file.
I really don't think it was her,
and I'm not convinced Danny should be
back at work.
Well, it was only a little snake.
Jean?
I'm a little bit stuck. I'd love
a chat, but if you're busy...
Oh, I think I can manage.
Is this about the Connollys?
Yes.
Turns out she's not having an affair.
He was, with one of his boarders.
The chap who died.
Oh!
Would you have guessed?
No! He was always attentive.
Just like any married couple, eh?
Well, there's more
than one kind of marriage.
I was only married a very short time,
so I'm afraid I'm no expert.
Thing is, the basement was locked,
there was only one key.
Are you sure about that?
Well, there was another key,
but it was missing?
So, who else could get into that
basement?
Did Frank any other lovers?
Claire said quite a few,
but once Ray showed up on the scene,
that was that.
So, why else would you want
to put a snake in his car?
You know, they're a competitive
bunch, theses salesmen,
and apparently Ray was the best,
and it would appear someone
has stolen his book of contacts.
So, how would you like to go about
this, Dr Blake?
Danny? Yes.
Listen, I might need your help
with something.
Ah, Jean, allow me.
Now, are you ready?
I think so.
Danny, give us five minutes and then
come up, yes?
OK.
I sold you that machine.
We had a deal.
Well, I think we can do better.
You can't do better.
I'm the region's top seller.
Since Ray died. Care to give it a go,
Mr Churchill?
He already tried
and he couldn't do it.
Keen to have another go, Doctor.
And just to add a little bit of
a sweetener,
Mattie here could use a small
refrigerator.
This is my sale.
I'm sick to death of you scrimping
on spending
and then splashing out on whatever
SHE wants!
Oh, yes, that's right -
pretend to be innocent.
Ladies, ladies, I think we can find
something that keeps you both happy.
Same great machine, same price,
two free bags and a year's warranty.
I'll match it.
And you've already got the machine.
I've got one in my car.
How do you like ice-cold juice,
sweetheart?
I've got all the latest fridges
for you, cost price.
And that's better than you'll ever
be able to do.
It's killing me, but for someone as
pretty as yourself,
20% off cost, free delivery,
and the Constellation as we agreed,
and I've got the Constellation
in my car, if we're done.
I'll get my contact book.
But that's... wrong.
How can you get 20% off cost?
Only Ray could go that low.
Yes, that's interesting,
Mr Churchill.
The other day you couldn't beat Jim
here on the price of a vacuum.
Today you can,
and also today you can offer
tremendous discounts on fridges.
I thought that was solely Ray's
territory,
and I'm guessing that's probably
Ray's contact book,
the one you stole
after you murdered him.
This is my contact...
Mrs Connolly, do you have the key the
young constable returned to you?
Yes.
Thank you.
Identical.
The missing spare key to the basement
on your key ring, Mr Churchill.
This is my con...
Hey, stop! Stop there!
Stop!
Jean, see to Danny, please!
I'm fine!
Danny, are you alright?
We need to get you back to the
hospital.
Anything for a sale, Mr Churchill.
Told you not to go back to work.
I was feeling better.
You weren't ready.
Two days bed rest, minimum.
You're coming home with us
and taking it easy.
Oh, no, I might... go home.
Danny!
No, it'll be fine.
Afternoon.
Excuse me.
All good, just not quite ready to
exert himself.
Would you be interested in sitting
in on the interview?
Churchill?
Of course.
Listen, you say g'day.
I'll just be a moment.
Mattie.
You should go in and see him.
I'm sure he's just fine without me.
So, you and Frank Connolly
were lovers,
then Ray came on the scene.
Frank didn't want to know me
after that.
What about the snakes?
I knew where Frank
kept the spare key.
So you took it
and then you stole the snake.
Mmm.
Do you think
it's easy being like this?
Do you think I want to?
Mr Churchill...
I never asked for this.
You despise me, don't you?
I... I disgust you, don't I?
Mr Churchill, I spent some time
in a prisoner of war camp,
and there was a young man there,
he was executed just before we were
liberated.
He tried to steal medical supplies
to save his mates.
I had to read some of his letters to
get word back home,
and it was only then that I realised
the girlfriend he spoke of...
..wasn't a girl at all.
And he was the bravest man
I ever met.
I loved Frank.
But he loved someone else.
Yes?
Is it safe to come in?
Perhaps.
I just wanted to say thank you.
I still don't know
how you could afford
to buy us a brand-new vacuum cleaner
and a refrigerator.
Well, believe it or not,
I had a little win on the horses.
Oh!
Erm, happy birthday for tomorrow.
I hadn't forgotten.
Lucien!
Well, go on, open it.
Oh, thank you!
It's beautiful.
Was it hers?
No.
No, I, um... I bought it
before the Japanese invaded,
and I thought it might make a good
present one day,
and indeed it has.
Happy birthday, Jean.
Drop the gun!
This is about
Sean McBride,
who murdered
a policeman.
Apparently.
The bloke wanted
to die.
And you saw McBride kill that man?
I was there.
McBride confessed.
He killed Cooper
and took a shot
at Parks and Hobart.
There was a second wound
caused by a blow
to the back of the head
inflicted before
he was shot.
What would you say if I told you
I'd discovered certain links
between Sean McBride
and the police.
Do you know who
he passed
information on to?
The entire case
against Sean McBride
was circum-bloody-stantial!
He confessed!
It was a lie!
Admissions?
No!
Did McBride recant?
No
Then you've got nothing!
They want someone to hang!